Guide to the Cooperative Consumers' Society records, 1936-1982
Cooperative Consumers' Society records, 1936-1982
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cooperative Consumers' Society records, 1936-1982.
1689
Cooperative Consumers' Society (Ithaca, N.Y.)
17.7 cubic ft.
Minutes, correspondence, pamphlets, reports, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Materials relating to the activities of the Cooperative Consumers' Society, including records pertaining to store management, cooperation, volunteers, personnel, expansion, planning, construction, reopening, and other subjects. Also included are minutes and reports of the Board of Directors and Executive Committee; Education Committee materials; "Trade Winds," an employee publication; copies of the "Co-op Bulletin"; papers and a market survey analysis; and papers concerning the early history of the Co-op.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Cooperative Consumers' Society, Inc. was a cooperative food store in Ithaca, Tompkins County, New York. It was incorporated in 1936, after having been called the Tompkins County Consumers Club since its inception in 1934.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Form letters, reports, announcements, by-laws, union contracts, insurance reports, financial summaries, property appraisals, stock and debentures ledgers, publicity tracts, clippings, photographs, surveys, studies, membership lists, annual reports, correspondence, and other materials relating to the activities of the Cooperative Consumers' Society, including records pertaining to store management, cooperation, volunteers, personnel, expansion, planning, construction, plans to reopen the Co-op Food Store in 1980, and other subjects. Also included are minutes and reports of the Board of Directors and Executive Committee; Education Committee correspondence, minutes, advertisements, and other materials; "Trade Winds," an employee publication; copies of the "Co-op Bulletin"; papers and a market survey analysis by Peter May; and papers concerning the early history of the Co-op, by Edward Wilson, Paul W. Gates, and Hugh Cosline.
Also includes papers written for Cornell University course, Agricultural Economics 249 and other courses using the Co-op as their subject.
Consists of collections 1689 and 1083.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cooperative Consumers' Society (Ithaca, N.Y.); Cosline, Hugh.; Gates, Paul Wallace, 1901-; Wilson, Edward.; Tompkins County Consumers Club.
Titles:
Co-op bulletin.; Trade winds.
Subjects:
Consumer cooperatives.; Cooperative societies.; Grocery trade.; Market surveys.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Minutes of the meetings of the directors of the Co-operative Consumers' Society as well as those of various executive committees. (Box 1)
- Committee Reports, e.g. Store location committee, Operating Committee. (Box 1)
- Publicity tracts. (Box 1)
- Farm letters sent by the directors to the Membership. (Box 1)
- Financial Summaries & Insurance Reports. (Box 1)
- By-laws. (Box 1)
- Certificate of Amendment & of Increase of Capital Stock of C.C.S. (Box 1)
- Co-operative Consumers' Society Bulletins (Box 1)
- Outline of Qualifications of Applicants (Box 1)
- Menus of Society banquets (Box 1)
- A policy statement of the Education Committee - July 18, 1945. (Box 1)
- Enrolled Communist & Socialist Voters of Tompkins County ( 1936-1937 .) (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - S. L. Boothroyd, Pres., to Mr. Byron Mohrbacher, Asst. Mgr. of Store, Apr. 17, 1942 (Box 1)
    Accepts his resignation since latter feels he can't work harmoniously in store as at present organized.
  - Mr. Arthur J. Pratt to Mr. Phillip A. MacEachron, Oct. 16, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Robert D. Sweet to Mr. S. L. Boothroyd, Feb. 2, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Dan A. Williams to Frank O'Connell, Feb. 5, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Dan A. Williams to S. L. Boothroyd, Feb. 5, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Alice D. Mack (for League of Women Voters) to Board of Directors of C.C.S. in care of Mrs. Emma Lokken. (Box 1)
  - Paul W. Gates to Arthur J. Pratt, May 14, 1954 (Box 1)
- Board of Directors Minutes (Box 2)
- Board of Directors Minutes (Box 3)
- Minutes of Operations Committee (Box 4)
- Minutes of Membership/Education Committee (Box 4)
- Annual Meeting Minutes (Box 4)
- Board of Directors Election Material (Box 4)
- Union contracts (Box 5)
- Trade Winds - Employee Publication Aug. 1968 - Oct. 1969 (Box 5)
- Early Managers Financial Reports 1937-1940 (Box 5)
- Annual Reports - 1939, 1945, 1947, 1948, 1951-52 (Box 5)
- By-laws (Box 5)
- Property appraisals (1976 missing) 1968-1979 (Box 5)
- Coop bulletins (Box 5)
- Education Material - 1980 reopening and 1981 (Box 6)
- Adventure in Cooperation by Hugh Cosline (Box 6)
- A Report to the Cooperative Consumers Society of Ithaca by Carol & Gallant (Box 6)
- The Roles of Consumers Cooperatives & Supermarkets in the New York Food System by Peter May (Box 6)
- Report of the Ad Hoc Committee on Options for a Reopened Coop Foods Store May 6, 1980 (Box 6)
- History & Growth of the Ithaca Coop - author unknown (Box 6)
- Growth of a Coop Food Store by Edward Wilson (Box 6)
- Growth of the Coop Food Store 1948 by Paul W. Gates (Box 6)
- Growth of Ithaca Cooperative Consumers' Society - author unknown (Box 6)
- Marketing Strategy for the Coop by Peter May (Box 6)
- Cooperation... (Box 6)
- Coop Where People Get Together (Box 6)
- Strategy for Coop Survival Planning by Peter May (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 6)
- Some Good Reasons for Trading at the Coop (Box 6)
- "Troika" Circumstances Create a Successful Co-op by Bob Krause (Box 6)
- Report on Cooperative Consumers Society of Ithaca, NY prepared for Nationwide Insurance Mar. 11, 1977 (Box 6)
- Education Material (ads, etc.) 1980-1982 (Box 6)
- Telephone Tree 1980 (Box 6)
- Membership/Member Labor (Box 6)
- CCS Market Survey Analysis by Peter May, June 1981 (Box 6)
- Joint Committee CSS/IRFC (Box 6)
- Material on Beer Referendums (Box 6)
- Volunteer Coordination 1980-1982 (Box 6)
- 3 Months in British Isles by Ruth Deabler (Box 6)
- Expansion Plans 1956-1958 (Box 6)
- Construction 1965-1968 (Box 6)
- Renovations 1980 (Box 6)
- Cooperative Consumers Society Financial Trends by David Beckhorn, May 15, 1975 (Box 6)
- Long Range Properties Planning (Box 6)
- Co-Operation "Of the People, By the People, and For the People" (Box 6)
- Rotary News Article (Box 6)
- Do Co-ops Pay Taxes? (Box 6)
- Advantages of the Co-op (Box 6)
- Notice to Shoppers at the Co-op (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous untitled reports (Box 6)
- Studies by students (Box 7)
- Surveys (Box 7)
- News clippings (Box 7)
- Lettuce and grape boycott (Box 7)
- Photos (Box 8)
- Stockholder addresses (Box 9)
- Stockholder addresses (Box 10)
- Personnel Records (Box 11)
- Personnel Records and Common Stock Ledgers A-B (Box 12)
- Common Stock Ledgers C-Mc (Box 13)
- Common Stock Ledgers M-Z (Box 14)
- Stock and Debentures Ledgers A-K (Box 15)
- Stock and Debentures Ledgers L-Z (Box 16)
- Stock and Debentures Ledgers 6%, 8% A-Z (Box 17)
- Dues paying members 1981 (Box 17)